ROBERT LANIER

Data Engineer



About

Before becoming a Data Analyst, I was cyber security professional for 3 years in various roles. Prior to that, I had the opportunity to be a systems engineer for 7+ years. In my previous roles, I learned how to create data visualizations & reports using various tools and writing advanced search queries using Splunk's SPL to analyze complex machine data. I enjoyed the overwhelming sense of satisfaction I got from solving problems through advanced queries and scripts so much that I decided to enroll into Nashville Software School to become a Data Analyst, that has been the best decision for my career so far. I am now looking forward to contributing my previous technical experience, project management skills, and personable soft skills towards my first role as a Data Engineer.

Skills

- Python
- Numpy
- Pandas
- SQL
- Tableau
- Power BI
- Power Query
- Git / Github
- Splunk Enterprise
- Jira

- · Service Now Reports
- Confluence
- · Lean Six Sigma
- · Azure Sec Center
- VMware vCenter

Education

Data Analyst

Nashville Software School

AAS, Computer Networking Technology

Nashville State Community College

Technical Education

Nashville Software School

Part-time immersive Python / SQL / Tableau

Anticipated Grad. Jan. 2022

Six-month part-time project based immersive focused on hands-on, fast-moving and rigorous study of data analytics and business intelligence processes and tools, including Excel, SQL, Python, Tableau, and Power BI. Using real data presented by Nashville employers, when possible, learning included communicating findings through presentations, storytelling, and creating reports & dashboards. Onboarding process, instruction, and team work done remotely using Zoom. Highlights Include:

- Gained experience writing advanced SQL queries using subqueries, CTEs, and window functions.
- Gained experience with Extract, Transform, Load (ETL) workflows
- Used data visualization tools Tableau, Power BI, Matplotib, and Seaborn
- Created Jupyter Notebooks to analyze and document workflows using Python
- Used open sourced data for individual and group projects
- · Used data storytelling techniques to present data insights

Projects

Data Analyst Jobs | Individual Project | View Code

Loaded Indeed Jobs dataset from kaggle.com usng PgAdmin. Analyzed data using Postgres SQL queries and communicated findings through presentation, and data storytelling.

Tools & Skills: Postgres SQL, PgAdmin, Data Storytelling

GDP and Internet Usage | Individual Project | View Code

Loaded .csv into dataframe for analysis. Cleaned and analyzed data using Python to answer questions regarding dataset.

Created data visualizations using Python modules within Jupyter Notebooks.

• Tools & Skills: Python, Jupyter Notebooks, VSCode

App Trader | Team Project | View Code

Determined the most profitable mobile applications for fictional app brokerage firm. Recommended a top 10 list of mobile apps which should be purchased based off profitability. Communicated findings through PowerPoint presentation.

• Tools & Skills: Postgres SQL, PgAdmin, Data Storytelling

Lahman Baseball | Team Project | View Code

Used a dataset of 27 tables created by Sean Lahman and Postgres SQL to analyze baseball statistics, which required the use of joins, case statements, window functions, and common table expressions.

• Tools & Skills: Postgres SQL, PgAdmin, Data Storytelling

Professional Experience

Cloud Vulnerability Remediation Engineer Security Engineer / Penetration Tester Cyber Security SOC Analyst

2021 - Current

2020 - 2021

2017 - 2020

HCA Healthcare, Nashville, TN

- Utilized Splunk Enterprise to analyze machine generated data to correlate events, create dashboards, and design reports using SPL, which is similar to SQL
- Used Service Now to analyze ticket data and other data capture tools to design a monthly operations report (MOR) with tables and data visualizations
- Lead a database protection project, managed several security review projects, and lead several lean six sigma greenbelt projects
- Monitored and assisted in remediating SIEM alerts, and investigated phishing emails
- Created security reviews of vendor applications using Burp Suite Pro and lead the security remediation effort with the vendor application team
- Used **Jira** to manage project task and **Confluence** for documentation
- Lead efforts and collaborations across departments / silos to design a scalable cloud security posture remediation program.

Platform Engineer II

2015- 2017

HCA Healthcare, Nashville, TN

- Wintel Operations supports the majority of corporate infrastructure consisting of approximately 11,000 Windows server instances, 740
 VMware hosts, and 720 Citrix hosts. Our team includes support, lifecycle, and disaster recovery operations of non-clinical and some clinical Microsoft, VMware, and Citrix platforms
- Project lead for Windows Server 2000/2003 decomissioning / refresh project. Standardized and documented the project processes.
- Used System Center Configuration Manager (SCCM) to automate application upgrades and application installations.
- Subject Matter Expert for Trend Micro Deep Security an enterprise endpoint antivirus application providing agent deployment, maintenance, troubleshooting, and remediated security threats.
- Redesigned Trend Micro Deep Security Antivirus infrastructure which included over 3,600 servers, migrated servers from an older product to the current product with included an additional 3,000 servers
- · Collaborated with the Cyber Security Red Team for security testing of the product's intrusion prevention feature
- · Assisted in several disaster recovery exercises

Client IT Manager

2014 - 2015

Advanced Network Solutions, Nashville, TN

- Relationship Manager/Systems Engineer for a portfolio of several clients in the greater Nashville, TN areas.
- · Traveled to client offices for onsite support, configuration, and general security needs regarding their on-premise infrastructure
- · Managed Cisco, Fortinet, and Shoretel network devices as well as several different servers and endpoint devices
- Recommended solutions to technical challenges.

Systems Administrator

2010 - 2014

Healthcare Realty Trust, Nashville, TN

- Managed infrastructure which was over 95% virtualized utilizing VMware, Citrix, and Microsoft technologies
- Configured and deployed Cisco routers, firewalls (ASA), and switches.
- Lead the service desk for the company of over 200 employees

Certifications

- · CCNA Cyber Ops (expired)
- CCNA Network Security (expired)
- CCNA Routing & Switching (expired)
- Comptia Security+

- VMware VCP-NV (expired)
- VMware VCP-DCV (expired)
- ITILv3 Foundation
- Lean Six Sigma Greenbelt (currently pursuing)